A Finding Aid to the Adolph A. Weinman Papers, 1890-1959, in the Archives of American Art AAA.weinadol
Archives of American Art
- Project Files, 1896-circa 1955; Series 8; (Boxes 3-8, 10-14, OVs 15-22; Reels 5888-5891; 6.0 linear feet)
  - Sculptor's Mother (Portrait Medallion of Catharina Weinman), 1896; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 374-382)
  - Portrait Medallion of Ada Landman, 1897 (Reel 5888, Frame 383-384)
  - Portrait Medallion of Alice Helen Hettinger, 1898 (Reel 5888, Frame 385-387)
  - Portrait Medallion of Unidentified Man, circa 1900; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 388-389)
  - Bust of Margaret Lucille (wife), circa 1911; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 390-395)
  - Portrait Medallion of Margaret Lucille (wife), 1900 (Reel 5888, Frame 396-399)
  - Portrait Medallion of Dorothy, circa 1900 (Reel 5888, Frame 400-403)
  - Portrait Medallion of Louise Hettinger, 1900 (Reel 5888, Frame 404-405)
  - Relief Portrait of Louise Hettinger, 1900 (Reel 5888, Frame 406-407)
  - Sarah Porter Memorial Plaque, Farmington Lodge Society, 1901; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 408-409)
  - The Bowler, circa 1901; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 410-414)
  - Girl Golfer, circa 1901; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 415-416)
  - The Golfer, 1901; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 417-421)
  - The Pitcher, 1901; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 422-425)
  - Rockinghorse Baby, Portrait Medallion of Son, 1902; (see also Box 11) (Reel 5888, Frame 426-427)
  - Bust of Charles Henry Niehaus, circa 1903; (see also Box 11) (Reel 5888, Frame 428-430)
  - Strayed From the Herd, circa 1903; (see also Box 11) (Reel 5888, Frame 431-434)
  - Cow with Lowered Head, 1903; (see also Box 11) (Reel 5888, Frame 435-436)
  - Bell for Cruiser Cleveland (Reel 5888)
    - Correspondence, 1903-1904 (Reel 5888, Frame 438-440)
    - Clippings, 1903 (Reel 5888, Frame 441-448)
    - Photographs, circa 1903 (Reel 5888, Frame 449-452)
  - Bust of Womboli, Sioux Indian Boy, circa 1903-1904 (Reel 5888, Frame 453-456)
  - Chief Blackbird, circa 1903-1904 (Reel 5888, Frame 457-464)
  - Chief Flatiron, circa 1903-1904; (see also Box 11) (Reel 5888, Frame 465-466)
  - Destiny of the Red Man (Reel 5888)
    - Contract, 1903 (Reel 5888, Frame 468-471)
    - Printed Material, 1904, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 472-483)
    - Photographs, circa 1903-1904; (3 folders; see also Box 11) (Reel 5888, Frame 484-496)
  - Kansas, circa 1904; (see also Box 11) (Reel 5888, Frame 497-502)
  - Louisiana Purchase Exposition Medals, Letters and Photographs, 1904-1905; (3 folders; see also Box 11) (Reel 5888, Frame 503-514)
  - Theodore Roosevelt Inaugural Medal (designed by Augustus Saint-Gaudens), 1905; (see also Box 11) (Reel 5888, Frame 515-519)
  - Music Inspiring the Arts and Truth and the Sciences, Panels for Facade of J. Pierpont Morgan Library, New York, New York, 1905; (see also Box 11) (Reel 5888, Frame 520-522)
  - George Poell Medal for Lifesaving on Railroads, 1905-1906; (see also Box 11) (Reel 5888, Frame 523-527)
  - Madison Square Presbyterian Church Pediment, New York, New York, circa 1906; (see also Box 11) (Reel 5888, Frame 528-531)
  - Alexander Macomb Memorial, Detroit, Michigan (Reel 5888)
    - Contracts and Drawing, 1906-1908, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 533-542)
    - Correspondence, 1906-1908 (Reel 5888, Frame 543-558)
    - Clippings, 1908 (Reel 5888, Frame 559-569)
    - Photographs, 1906-1908; (5 folders; see also Box 11) (Reel 5888, Frame 570-595)
  - American Institute of Architects Medal, 1907; (includes one letter from Charles F. McKim) (Reel 5888, Frame 596-598)
  - Union Soldiers and Sailors Monument, Baltimore, Maryland (Reel 5888)
    - Contracts, 1907-1909 (Reel 5888, Frame 600-620)
    - Correspondence, 1908-1912 (Reel 5888, Frame 621-632)
    - Drawings and Blueprints, 1907, undated; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5888, Frame 633-641)
    - Clipping, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 642-643)
    - Photographs, circa 1908-1910; (2 folders; see also Box 11) (Reel 5888, Frame 644-663)
  - Seated Lincoln Statue Hodgenville, Kentucky (Reel 5888)
    - Contracts, 1907-1909 (Reel 5888, Frame 665-673)
    - Correspondence, 1909-1911 (Reel 5888, Frame 674-688)
    - Drawings and Blueprint, 1909-1925, undated; (see also OV 22) (Reel 5888, Frame 689-696)
    - Clippings, 1923, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 697-701)
    - Photographs, 1931-circa 1955, undated; (5 folders; see also Box 11) (Reel 5888, Frame 702-731)
  - William Bateman Leeds Mausoleum Panel, Woodlawn Cemetery, New York, 1908; (see also Box 11) (Reel 5888, Frame 732-734)
  - Alexander Johnston Cassatt Statue, Pennsylvania Railroad Terminal, New York, New York (Reel 5888)
    - Contract, 1908 (Reel 5888, Frame 736-740)
    - Correspondence, 1910 (Reel 5888, Frame 741-746)
    - Clipping, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 747-748)
    - Photographs, undated; (3 folders; see also Box 12) (Reel 5888, Frame 749-772)
  - Seated Lincoln Statue, University of Wisconsin (Reel 5888)
    - Meeting Minutes, Contracts, Notes, 1908-1909 (Reel 5888, Frame 774-783)
    - Drawings and Blueprint, 1908-1913, undated; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5888, Frame 784-791)
    - Program and Clippings, 1909-1917 (Reel 5888, Frame 792-801)
    - Photographs, undated; (see also Box 12) (Reel 5888, Frame 802-810)
  - Monument to Civil War Soldiers and Sailors, Albany, New York, 1909; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5888, Frame 811-814)
  - Wisconsin State Capitol Pediment (Reel 5888)
    - Contracts, 1909 (Reel 5888, Frame 816-825)
    - Photographs, 1909; (see also Box 12) (Reel 5888, Frame 826-829)
  - Lincoln Memorial, Oshkosh, Wisconsin, 1909 (Reel 5888, Frame 830-831)
  - Miscellaneous Sculptures for Pennsylvania Railroad Station, New York, New York, 1910; (see also Box 12) (Reel 5888, Frame 832-844)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters Medal, circa 1910; (see also Box 12) (Reel 5888, Frame 845-846)
  - Relief Portrait of Gilbert Montague Stark, circa 1910; (see also Box 12) (Reel 5888, Frame 847-848)
  - Unidentified Tablet Drawing, 1910; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5888, Frame 849-850)
  - Julius Theodore Melchers Memorial Plaque, 1910; (see also Box 12) (Reel 5888, Frame 851-852)
  - Standing Lincoln Statue, Kentucky State Capitol Rotunda (Reel 5888)
    - Contract, 1910 (Reel 5888, Frame 854-858)
    - Correspondence, 1911 (Reel 5888, Frame 859-864)
    - Clippings, 1917 (Reel 5888, Frame 865-869)
    - Photographs, 1910; (4 folders; see also Box 12) (Reel 5888, Frame 870-888)
  - William Cotter Maybury Memorial, Detroit, Michigan (Reel 5888)
    - Contract, Letter, Drawings, 1911-1912; (see also OV 22) (Reel 5888, Frame 890-903)
    - Clippings, 1911-1912 (Reel 5888, Frame 904-908)
    - Photographs, undated; (see also Box 12) (Reel 5888, Frame 909-912)
  - Municipal Building Sculpture, New York, New York, 1911-1913; (2 folders; see also Box 12) (Reel 5888, Frame 913-925)
  - Masonic Temple Tympanum, San Francisco, California, 1912; (see also Box 12) (Reel 5888, Frame 926-928)
  - Lincoln Bust Replica for Loraine Pratt-Immen, Grand Rapids, Michigan (Reel 5888)
    - Contract, 1912 (Reel 5888, Frame 930-933)
    - Drawings, Blueprint, Clipping, 1912, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 934-938)
    - Photographs, 1912; (see also Box 12) (Reel 5888, Frame 939-943)
  - William F. Vilas Memorial, Vicksburg, Mississippi (Reel 5888)
    - Contracts, 1912 (Reel 5888, Frame 945-954)
    - Letters and Clipping, 1912, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 955-959)
    - Photographs, 1912-1914; (2 folders; see also Box 12 and 14) (Reel 5888, Frame 960-980)
  - Sphinxes and Crowned Eagle, Scottish Rite Temple, Washington, D.C. (Reel 5888)
    - Contract, Letter, Drawings, 1912-1915, undated; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5888, Frame 982-994)
    - Clippings, 1913-1915 (Reel 5888, Frame 995-999)
    - Photographs, undated; (see also Box 12) (Reel 5888, Frame 1000-1009)
  - Relief Portrait of Anna M. Dietsche, circa 1913 (Reel 5888, Frame 1010-1012)
  - Sir Galahad Sculptured Lectern, George Newhall Clarke Memorial Chapel, Pomfret School, Pomfret, Connecticut Photographs, circa 1913; (see also Box 13) (Reel 5888, Frame 1013-1015)
  - Reredos with Kneeling Angels, George Newhall Clarke Memorial Chapel, Pomfret School, Pomfret, Connecticut Clipping and Photographs, 1913; (see also Box 13) (Reel 5888, Frame 1016-1021)
  - The Rising Sun and Descending Night, Panama-Pacific International Exposition, San Francisco, California (Reel 5888)
    - Contracts and Copyright Cards, 1913-1915 (Reel 5888, Frame 1023-1035)
    - Correspondence, 1913-1916; (includes letters from Karl Bitter and Stirling Calder; 4 folders) (Reel 5888, Frame 1036-1086)
    - Drawing and Clippings, 1915, undated; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5888, Frame 1087-1093)
    - Photographs, undated; (5 folders; see also Box 13) (Reel 5888, Frame 1094-1141)
  - Cartouche, John Innes Kane House, New York, New York Letter and Art Work, 1914 (Reel 5888, Frame 1142-1144)
  - Winged Liberty ("Mercury") Dime and Walking Liberty Half-Dollar (Reel 5888)
    - Correspondence from the U. S. Mint, 1915-1916 (Reel 5888, Frame 1146-1164)
    - Clippings, 1916-1922 (Reel 5888, Frame 1165-1172)
    - Photograph of the Winged Liberty Dime, undated; (see also Box 13) (Reel 5888, Frame 1173-1174)
  - Portrait Medallion of Howard K. Weinman, 1917 (Reel 5888, Frame 1175-1176)
  - William H. Perry Bas Relief, Bridgeport, Connecticut, 1917-1919 (Reel 5888, Frame 1178-1185)
  - Victory Button, 1919; (2 folders) (Reel 5888, Frame 1186-1204)
  - Memorial Tablet, Soldiers Welcome Home Committee, Forest Hills, New York (Reel 5888)
    - Contract and Correspondence, 1920-1921; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5888, Frame 1206-1217)
    - Clippings, 1920 (Reel 5888, Frame 1218-1222)
    - Photograph, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 1223-1225)
  - Mount Sinai Medals, World War I Medical Service Medal and Trustees Service Award Medal, 1920, 1927; (2 folders) (Reel 5888, Frame 1226-1234)
  - Bust of Benjamin Harrison, John Herron Art Institute, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1920; (2 folders; see also Box 14) (Reel 5888, Frame 1235-1245)
  - J. Sanford Saltus Medal, American Numismatic Society, circa 1921; (see also Box 13) (Reel 5888, Frame 1246-1249)
  - The Mourning Victory War Memorial Tablet Copyright Card, 1921 (Reel 5888, Frame 1250-1252)
  - War Memorial, Pottstown, Pennsylvania Contract and Copyright Cards, 1921 (Reel 5888, Frame 1253-1262)
  - Speyer Grave Memorial, Sleepy Hollow Cemetery, Tarrytown, New York (Reel 5888)
    - Contracts, 1921 (Reel 5888, Frame 1264-1272)
    - Letters from James Speyer, 1923 (Reel 5888, Frame 1273-1275)
    - Photographs, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 1276-1278)
  - Missouri State Capitol Pediment, Jefferson City, Missouri (Reel 5888)
    - Contract, 1923 (Reel 5888, Frame 1280-1283)
    - Correspondence, 1921-1927; (6 folders) (Reel 5888, Frame 1284-1375)
    - Photograph, undated; (see also Box 13) (Reel 5888, Frame 1376-1377)
  - On Nimble Toe Bronze Copyright Cards and Photographs, 1922, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 1378-1383)
  - Bust of Horace Mann, New York University Hall of Fame, University Heights, New York (Reel 5888)
    - Correspondence, 1929-1934 (Reel 5888, Frame 1385-1407)
    - Blueprint, 1922; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5888, Frame 1408-1410)
    - Photographs, 1930, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 1411-1416)
  - Duet Statue Copyright Cards and Photographs, 1922-1937, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 1417-1425)
  - William J. Gaynor Memorial Bridge, Nassay and New Streets, New York, New York, Contracts, 1923 (Reel 5888, Frame 1426-1462)
    - Letters and Program, 1924-1926 (Reel 5889, Frame 12-19)
    - Photographs, undated (Reel 5889, Frame 20-24)
  - Elks National Memorial Headquarters Building, Frieze and Façade Figures, Chicago, Illinois (Reel 5889)
    - Contracts, 1923-1926 (Reel 5889, Frame 26-40)
    - Correspondence, 1923-1942; (2 folders) (Reel 5889, Frame 41-72)
    - Drawings, undated (Reel 5889, Frame 73-76)
    - Clippings, 1954 (Reel 5889, Frame 77-83)
    - Photographs of Building Exterior, undated; (see also Box 13) (Reel 5889, Frame 84-90)
    - Photographs of "Fraternity" Sculpture Group, undated; (see also Box 13) (Reel 5889, Frame 91-98)
    - Photographs "Patriotism" Sculpture Group, undated; (see also Box 13) (Reel 5889, Frame 99-112)
    - Photographs of Entire Frieze, undated; (see also Box 13) (Reel 5889, Frame 113-119)
    - Photographs of "Terror of War" Frieze Figures, undated; (see also Box 13) (Reel 5889, Frame 120-134)
    - Photographs of "Glory of Peace" Frieze Figures, undated; (see also Box 13) (Reel 5889, Frame 135-160)
  - Singer of the Epic Song, Adolph Weinman Residence/Studio, Forest Hills, New York, circa 1924; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5889, Frame 161-169)
  - Pegasus Rondell, Adolph Weinman Residence/Studio, Forest Hills, New York (Reel 5889)
    - Clippings, 1924 (Reel 5889, Frame 171-172)
    - Photographs, 1924 (Reel 5889, Frame 173-177)
  - Relocation of Sculpture by Karl Bitter and Fountain, Missouri State Capitol, Jefferson City, Missouri (Reel 5889)
    - Contract, 1926 (Reel 5889, Frame 179-185)
    - Correspondence, 1925-March 1926 (Reel 5889, Frame 186-241)
    - Correspondence, April 1926-August 1926 (Reel 5889, Frame 242-305)
    - Correspondence, September 1926-1927 (Reel 5889, Frame 306-362)
    - Blueprint of Fountain, undated; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5889, Frame 363-368)
    - Photographs, undated; (3 folders; see also Box 13) (Reel 5889, Frame 369-392)
  - Samuel Rea Statue, Pennsylvania Railroad Terminal, New York, New York (Reel 5889)
    - Contracts, 1926 (Reel 5889, Frame 394-400)
    - Letters and Clipping, 1926, undated (Reel 5889, Frame 401-406)
    - Photographs and Negatives, 1930, undated; (4 folders; see also Box 13-14) (Reel 5889, Frame 407-439)
  - Monfaucon American Memorial, Meuse-Argonne Battlefield, France (Reel 5889)
    - Correspondence, 1928-1931 (Reel 5889, Frame 441-521)
    - Correspondence, 1932 (Reel 5889, Frame 522-587)
    - Blueprint and Clipping, 1930-1931; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5889, Frame 588-590)
    - Photographs, undated; (5 folders) (Reel 5889, Frame 591-605)
  - DeWitt Clinton and Alexander Hamilton Statues, Museum of the City of New York facade, New York, New York (Reel 5889)
    - Contracts, 1939 (Reel 5889, Frame 607-619)
    - Correspondence, 1929-1939 (Reel 5889, Frame 620-673)
    - Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Reel 5889, Frame 674-758)
    - Clippings, 1941, undated (Reel 5889, Frame 759-761)
    - Notes Concerning DeWitt Clinton, undated (Reel 5889, Frame 762-772)
    - Photographs of DeWitt Clinton Portrait Busts by Others, undated (Reel 5889, Frame 773-793)
    - Photographs of Wire Model for DeWitt Clinton Statue, undated (Reel 5889, Frame 794-800)
    - Photographs of DeWitt Clinton Statue, undated (Reel 5889, Frame 801-829)
    - Photographs of Alexander Hamilton Portraits by Others, undated (Reel 5889, Frame 830-851)
    - Photographs of Alexander Hamilton Statue, undated (Reel 5889, Frame 852-871)
  - The Last Farewell Figure, Arlington National Cemetery Entrance and Bridge, Arlington, Virginia (Reel 5889)
    - Contract, 1935 (Reel 5889, Frame 874-882)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1935; (see also OV 22) (Reel 5889, Frame 883-940)
    - Correspondence, 1936; (see also OV 22) (Reel 5889, Frame 941-989)
    - Correspondence, 1937-1939; (see also OV 22) (Reel 5889, Frame 990-1017)
    - Correspondence, 1944-1949; (see also OV 22) (Reel 5889, Frame 1018-1040)
    - Correspondence, 1950; (see also OV 22) (Reel 5889, Frame 1041-1133)
    - Correspondence, 1951; (see also OV 22) (Reel 5889, Frame 1134-1186)
    - Correspondence, 1952; (see also OV 22) (Reel 5889, Frame 1187-1282)
    - Correspondence, 1953 (Reel 5890, Frame 13-42)
    - Drawings and Blueprints, 1931-1935, undated; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5890, Frame 43-48)
    - Photographs, undated; (5 folders) (Reel 5890, Frame 49-80)
  - New York Women's League for Animals Honor Medal, 1930 (Reel 5890, Frame 81-83)
  - William C. C. Claiborne Statue and Entrance Frieze, Baton Rouge, Louisiana (Reel 5890)
    - Contracts, 1931 (Reel 5890, Frame 85-93)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1933 (Reel 5890, Frame 94-118)
    - Notes, Blueprint, Clipping, 1930-1932; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5890, Frame 119-126)
    - Photographs, undated; (6 folders; see also Box 14) (Reel 5890, Frame 127-173)
  - U. S. Post Office Department Pediments, Washington, D.C. (Reel 5890)
    - Contracts, 1932-1933; (3 folders) (Reel 5890, Frame 175-254)
    - Correspondence, 1931 (Reel 5890, Frame 255-287)
    - Correspondence, 1932 (Reel 5890, Frame 288-336)
    - Correspondence, January-June 1933 (Reel 5890, Frame 337-441)
    - Correspondence, July-December 1933 (Reel 5890, Frame 442-597)
    - Correspondence, January-July 1934 (Reel 5890, Frame 598-641)
    - Correspondence, August 1934-1935 (Reel 5890, Frame 642-709)
    - Notes, Drawing, Blueprints, Clipping, 1931-1933, undated; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5890, Frame 710-718)
    - Photographs, undated; (5 folders) (Reel 5890, Frame 719-738)
  - U. S. Supreme Court Friezes, Washington, D. C. (Reel 5890)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1932; (including letters from Cass Gilbert) (Reel 5890, Frame 741-768)
    - Correspondence, 1933; (including letters from Cass Gilbert) (Reel 5890, Frame 769-826)
    - Correspondence, 1934; (including letters from Cass Gilbert) (Reel 5890, Frame 827-925)
    - Correspondence, 1935-1936; (including letters from Cass Gilbert) (Reel 5890, Frame 926-945)
    - Notes, undated; (4 folders) (Reel 5890, Frame 946-1041)
    - Photographs of Portraits of William Blackstone and John Marshall, undated (Reel 5890, Frame 1042-1044)
    - Photographs of Drawing of Supreme Court Chamber, undated (Reel 5890, Frame 1045-1046)
    - Photographs of Frieze, undated (Reel 5890, Frame 1047-1049)
    - Photographs of the North Frieze, undated (Reel 5890, Frame 1050-1067)
    - Photographs of the South Frieze, undated (Reel 5890, Frame 1068-1080)
    - Photographs of the East Frieze, undated (Reel 5890, Frame 1081-1092)
    - Photographs of the West Frieze, undated (Reel 5890, Frame 1093-1109)
  - Sculptural Groups, Bronx County Building, Bronx, New York (Reel 5890)
    - Contracts, 1931-1932 (Reel 5890, Frame 1111-1124)
    - Correspondence and Clipping, 1932-1936 (Reel 5890, Frame 1125-1141)
  - Oscar S. Straus Memorial, Washington, D. C. (Reel 5890)
    - Contracts and Financial Records, 1939-1942 (Reel 5890, Frame 1143-1171)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1934; (see also OV 21) (Reel 5890, Frame 1172-1194)
    - Correspondence, 1935-1939; (see also OV 21) (Reel 5890, Frame 1195-1248)
    - Correspondence, 1940; (see also OV 21) (Reel 5890, Frame 1249-1304)
    - Correspondence, 1941; (see also OV 21) (Reel 5890, Frame 1305-1368)
    - Correspondence, 1942-1946; (see also OV 21) (Reel 5890, Frame 1369-1416)
    - Correspondence, 1947-1948; (see also OV 21) (Reel 5891, Frame 14-51)
    - Notes and Blueprints, 1940-1947, undated; (see also OV 21) (Reel 5891, Frame 53-64a)
    - Clipping, Program, Booklet, 1947, undated (Reel 5891, Frame 64b, 65-79)
    - Photographs, undated (Reel 5891, Frame 80-84)
  - Cyrus McCormick Portrait Bust, State Capitol Hall of Fame, Richmond, Virginia (Reel 5891)
    - Correspondence and Clipping, 1932-1933 (Reel 5891, Frame 86-93)
    - Photographs, undated; (2 folders) (Reel 5891, Frame 94-100)
  - National Archives Pediment, Washington D. C. (Reel 5891)
    - Contracts, 1933-1934 (Reel 5891, Frame 102-125)
    - Correspondence, 1933 (Reel 5891, Frame 127-168)
    - Correspondence, 1934 (Reel 5891, Frame 169-296)
    - Correspondence, 1935 (Reel 5891, Frame 297-389)
    - Photographs, undated; (see also OV 22) (Reel 5891, Frame 390-395)
  - Bronze Doors, American Academy of Arts and Letters, New York, New York (Reel 5891)
    - Contract, 1935 (Reel 5891, Frame 397-400)
    - Correspondence, 1935-1938; (5 folders) (Reel 5891, Frame 401-476)
    - Drawing, 1937 (Reel 5891, Frame 477-478)
    - Photographs, undated (Reel 5891, Frame 479-488)
  - Mary A. Spencer Grave Memorial Remembrance, Rock Creek Cemetery, Washington, D.C. (Reel 5891)
    - Contracts, 1936-1937 (Reel 5891, Frame 490-494)
    - Correspondence, 1936 (Reel 5891, Frame 495-555)
    - Correspondence, 1937 (Reel 5891, Frame 556-668)
    - Correspondence, 1938-1941 (Reel 5891, Frame 669-679)
    - Drawing of Memorial Figure, undated; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5891, Frame 680-681)
    - Photographs, undated; (3 folders) (Reel 5891, Frame 682-712)
  - Church of Our Lady Queen of Martyrs, Forest Hills, New York (Reel 5891)
    - Correspondence, 1938-1941; (2 folders) (Reel 5891, Frame 714-746)
    - Notes, undated (Reel 5891, Frame 747-756)
  - Jefferson Memorial Competition and Pediment, Washington, D.C. (Reel 5891)
    - Contracts, 1939 (Reel 5891, Frame 758-773)
    - Prospectus, undated (Reel 5891, Frame 774-786)
    - Correspondence, 1937-1939 (Reel 5891, Frame 787-815)
    - Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Reel 5891, Frame 816-863)
    - Notes, undated (Reel 5891, Frame 864-872)
    - Drawings, undated; (see also OV 21) (Reel 5891, Frame 873-879)
    - Clippings, 1938-1943 (Reel 5891, Frame 880-885)
    - Photographs, undated; (5 folders) (Reel 5891, Frame 886-912)
  - Criminal Courts Building Statues, New York, New York, 1939 (Reel 5891, Frame 913-918)
  - Norton Grave Memorial, Greenwood Cemetery, Shreveport, Louisiana (Reel 5891)
    - Contracts, 1941-1942 (Reel 5891, Frame 920-931)
    - Correspondence, 1942-1946 (Reel 5891, Frame 932-949)
    - Photographs, undated (Reel 5891, Frame 950-953)
  - Service Medals, Theater of Operations (Reel 5891)
    - Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Reel 5891, Frame 955-1035)
    - Correspondence, 1944 (Reel 5891, Frame 1036-1066)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Reel 5891, Frame 1067-1121)
    - Drawings, undated (Reel 5891, Frame 1122-1124)
    - Clippings, 1946 (Reel 5891, Frame 1125-1126)
    - Photographs of Designs, undated; (2 folders) (Reel 5891, Frame 1127-1142)
  - Destiny of the Red Man (Replica from the Louisiana Purchase Exposition) for Richard W. Norton, Shreveport, Louisiana (Reel 5891)
    - Contracts, 1944-1945 (Reel 5891, Frame 1144-1153)
    - Correspondence, 1943-1947; (4 folders) (Reel 5891, Frame 1154-1220)
  - Figure of World War II Soldier, circa 1945 (Reel 5891, Frame 1221-1225)
  - Riders of the Dawn, Brookgreen Gardens, Brookgreen, South Carolina (Reel 5891)
    - Contract, 1942 (Reel 5891, Frame 1227-1230)
    - Correspondence, 1941-1944 (Reel 5891, Frame 1231-1303)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Reel 5891, Frame 1304-1332)
    - Notes, Drawings, Blueprint, Clipping, 1945, undated; (see also OV 21) (Reel 5891, Frame 1333-1347)
    - Photographs, 1946, undated; (see also OV 21; 11 folders) (Reel 5891, Frame 1348-1414)
  - Medal Honoring General George Marshall (Reel 5891)
    - Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Reel 5891, Frame 1416-1441)
    - Drawings, undated (Reel 5891, Frame 1442-1449)
  - Aphrodite, Richard W. Norton Art Foundation, Shreveport, Louisiana (Reel 5891)
    - Contract, 1950 (Reel 5891, Frame 1451-1454)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Reel 5891, Frame 1455-1494)
    - Correspondence, January-February 1950 (Reel 5891, Frame 1495-1545)
    - Correspondence, March-August 1950 (Reel 5892, Frame 13-97)
    - Correspondence, September-December 1950 (Reel 5892, Frame 98-157)
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Reel 5892, Frame 158-236)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Reel 5892, Frame 237-294)
    - Notes, undated (Reel 5892, Frame 295-314)
    - Photograph, undated (Reel 5892, Frame 315-316)
  - Glass Plate Negatives of Various Projects, 1896-1954, undated (Box 13)
    - Couple in Long Robes, undated (Box 13)
      1 glass plate negative
    - Angel Casting Out Male Figures, undated (Box 13)
    - Soldier and Sailor with Flag, undated (Box 13)
    - Winged Figure Balanced on Sphere with Flag, undated (Box 13)
    - Plaque with Two Mourning Cherubs, undated (Box 10)
    - Arch Flanked by Allegorical Figures, undated (Box 13)